Guide to the Richard Bruce Nugent Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Drafts of and correspondence relating to posthumously published work by Nugent, 1995-2007; Series VII; (17 boxes)
  - Gentleman Jigger -- Manuscript with Corrections by Don Weise, July 2007; pp 1-174 (Box 70)
    Weise was the editor at Carroll and Graf who purchased Gentleman Jigger
  - Gentleman Jigger -- Manuscript with Corrections by Don Weise, July 2007; pp 175-364 (Box 70)
  - Gentleman Jigger -- Manuscript with Corrections by Don Weise, July 2007; pp 365-423 finis (Box 70)
- Writings by others about Nugent, 1983-2009; Series VIII; (4 boxes)
  - Evans, Rodney. "Brother to Brother" Screenplay, 2001; 1 Item (Box 71)
    Xerox of typescript. 116 Pages
  - Evans, Rodney. "Brother to Brother" Website, 2005 (Box 71)
    Printout of text & images from the film's official website. 27 pages.
  - Evans, Rodney. "Brother to Brother" Reviews & Publicity, 2002-2006; Numerous Items (Box 71)
  - Garber, Eric. "Richard Bruce Nugent, 1986; 4 Items (Box 71)
  - Goeser, Caroline. "The Case of Ebony and Topaz: Racial and Sexual Hybridity in Harlem Renaissance Illustrations., ca 2007; 1 Item (Box 71)
  - Harris, E. Lynn. "Renaissance Men, 1999; 1 Item (Box 71)
    Single page extracted from The Advocate, March 2, 1999, p. 49.
  - Harris, Reginald. "Out, No Doubt, 2004; 1 Item (Box 71)
    July-August 2004 issue of Black Issues Book Review, in which this article appeares on pp. 36-38.
  - Internet, Several Items (Box 71)
    Printouts of various entries & articles on Nugent.
  - Jordan, Joseph. "Fire Burns Anew, 1983; 3 Items (Box 71)
  - McBreen, Ellen. "Richard Bruce Nugent's Salome of 1930: The Spectacle of Homosexuality in the Harlem Renaisssance, 1994-96; 2 Items (Box 71)
    1. Printout of the paper as submitted to Professor Robert Lubar, 1994 2. Printout of the paper as presented at the College Art Association conference, 1996
  - McBreen, Ellen. "Biblical Gender Bending in Harlem: The Queer Performance of Nugent's Salome, 1998; 1 Item (Box 72)
  - McGruder, Kevin. "Richard Bruce Nugent: Black, Gay, Rebellious, 2001; 1 Item (Box 72)
    Issue of Brooklyn Pride, Volume 1, Number 1 (February 2001) in which this article appeared.
  - Molesworth, Charles. "In Search of Sahdji: Alain Locke and the Making of an African-American Ballet, 2006; 1 Item (Box 72)
    Berlin Journal, Number 12 (Spring 2006), in which this article appears on pp. 56-59.
  - Miller, Michael S. "Activism in the Harlem Renaissance, 2008; 1 Item (Box 72)
    The Gay & Lesbian Review, Volume 15, Number 1 (January-February 2008) in which this essay appears on pp. 30-33.
  - Penn, Carol A. L. "An Interview with Mr. Bruce Nugent, 1983; 1 Item (Box 72)
    Harlem Cultural Review, Volume 5, Number 1 (September 1983) in which this article appears on p. 2.
  - Reid, Mark A. "Four Works by Richard Bruce Nugent, 1985; 2 Items (Box 72)
    Printout of the above paper, together with the envelope in which it was sent to Nugent.
  - Schmidt, Tyler. "'in the glad flesh of my fear': corporeal inscriptions in Richard Bruce Nugent's Geisha Man, 2003; 1 Item (Box 72)
    Printout of a draft of this essay. A few marginal markings by Wirth. 23 pp.
  - Schwarz, A. B. Christa. "Exploring Gay Harlem" & "Richard Bruce Nugent: The Quest for Beauty, 1999; 7 Items (Box 72)
    Printouts of two chapters from Schwarz's thesis, with comments by Wirth and letter & email to Wirth from Schwarz
  - Schwarz, A. B. Christa. "Gay Voices of the Harlem Renaissance, 1999; 2 Items (Box 72)
    PhD thesis, University of Sussex. 274 +ix pages. With one page of handwritten notes by Wirth
  - Silberman, Seth. "Looking for Richard Bruce Nugent and Wallace Henry Thurman: Reclaiming Black Male Same-Sexualities in the New Negro Movement, 1996; 1 Item (Box 73)
    Xerox copy of the article from In Process, Volume 1 (1996), pp. 53-73
  - Silberman, Seth. "Lighting the Harlem Renaissance AFire!!: Embodying Richard Bruce Nugent's Bohemian Politic, 2000; 1 Item (Box 73)
    Printout of the manuscript of this essay that appeared in The Greatest Taboo: Homosexuality in Black Communities, edited by Delroy Constantine-Simms (Los Angeles & New York, 2001), pp. 254-273.
  - Silberman, Seth. "Reading Black Queer Vernacular in the "Streetgeist and Folklore" of Harlem's Renaissance, 2003; 2 Items (Box 73)
    Printout ofthe manuscript of this essay that appeared in European Contributions to American Studies, Volume 53 (2004), pp. 129-152, with a covering letter to Wirth
  - Silberman, Seth. "'He Knew the Beauty of the Narrow Blue': Richard Bruce Nugent, the Harlem Renaisance, and the Performance of a Black Bohemian Episemology, 1996; 2 Items (Box 73)
    Printout of Silberman's Master's Thesis from the University of Maryland, with a page of notes by Wirth. 187 + pages
  - Smith, Charles Michael. "Harlem Renaissance Bohemian, 1987; 1 Item (Box 73)
    Clipping of the article, which appeared in New York Native on March 23, 1987.
  - Washington, Michele. "Souls on Fire, 1998; 1 Item (Box 73)
    Issue of Print, Volume 52, Number 2 (May-June 1998) in which this article appears on pp. 56-65. Illustrations include several Nugent images.
  - Willis, Steve. "Passing Ceremonies, 2000; 5 Items (Box 73)
    1. Printout of the playscript (66 pp.) with annotations by Wirth 2. Covering letter from Willis to Wirth 3. Notes by Wirth
  - Willis, Steve. "Passing Ceremonies, 2000; 1 Item (Box 74)
    Printout of the revised playscript (72 pp.)
  - Willis, Steve. "Passing Ceremonies, 2000-2009; Numerous Items (Box 74)
  - Willis, Steve. "Smoke, Lilies and Jade, 2000; 2 Items (Box 74)
    Printout of the playscript (18 pp.) together with a letter of transmission to Wirth
  - Wirth, Thomas. "Nugent, Richard Bruce" in American National Biography Online, 2002; Several Items (Box 74)
    Printout of the article (4 pp.) with printouts of the manuscript as submitted, the copyedited manuscript with further annotations by Wirth, associated correspondence with Oxford University Press, and the contract between Wirth and the press.
  - Wirth, Thomas. "Richard Bruce Nugent" in Black American Literature Forum, Volume 19, Number 1 (Spring 1985), pp. 16-17, 1984-85; 5 Items (Box 74)
    Copy of the publication, together with a printout of the manuscript, associated correspondence and contracts.
  - Wirth, Thomas. "Nugent, Richard Bruce" in Encyclopedia of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender History in America, Scribner's, 2003, 2002; 6 Items (Box 74)
    Printout of the manuscript, printouts of copyedited versions, with Wirth's responses, correspondence, and contract.
  - Wirth, Thomas. "Richard Bruce Nugent--Harlem Butterfly" in The Journal of the Leslie/Lohman Gay Art Foundation, Number 21 (Autumn 2006), 1 Item (Box 74)
    Copy of the publication.
  - Wirth, Thomas. Press releases and publicity material for The FIRE!! Press, 1982-1987; 6 Items (Box 74)
  - Wirth, Thomas. "Richard Bruce Nugent--Enfant Terrible of the Harlem Renaissance, 2008; 2 Items (Box 74)
    Manuscript in English of the article published in French in Harlem Heritage: memoires et renaissance, Riveneuve Continents, Numero hors serie (automne-hiver 2008-2009) pp. 27-35, together with a prospectus for the issue.
  - Wirth, Thomas. "Richard Bruce Nugend: Provocative Persona/Transgressive Artist, 2003; 1 Item (Box 74)
    Printout of the manuscript of a talk prepared for the Challenge of the Modern symposium scheduled for 2/17/2003. The symposium was cancelled due to inclement weather.
  - Wirth, Thomas. "Richard Bruce Nugent" in Transition 100 (2008), p. 132, 1 Item (Box 74)
    Printout of the manuscript.
- Third-party correspondence, 1946-2008; Series IX; (4 boxes)
  - Actor's Fund - Wirth, 1987-88; 2 Items (Box 75)
    1. Letter announcing a donation to the Actor's Fund in memory of Nugent from Eugene Stuckmann 2. Copy of the 1988 Annual Report in which the donation is listed.
  - Anderson, Vivienne - Carmel Marr, 1 Christmas Card (Box 75)
  - Barthe, Richmond - Bernard & Iva Kay, 1979-1982; 5 Letters; 1 Card (Box 75)
  - Boswell, Al to Wirth, 2001; 1 Letter (Box 75)
    Boswell played Nugent in the Chicago production of "Passing Ceremonies"
  - Cole, Margaret - Wirth, 1987; 1 Note (Box 75)
  - Condolences (to Wirth), 1987; 14 Letteers (Box 75)
  - Dernini, Sandro - Wirth, 1985-1988; 1 Card, 2 Postcards, 1 Letter, 1 Envelope (Box 75)
  - Giard, Robert - Wirth, 2003; 8 Items (Box 75)
    Correspondence relating to Giard's book, Particular Voices, including a copy of his photographic tribute to Nugent that was included therein and a request for permission to reprint part of "Smoke, Lilies & Jade."
  - Evans, Rodney - Wirth, 1999-2005; Numerous Items (Box 75)
    Letters and e-mail printouts relating to "Brother to Brother
  - Gomez, Jewelle - Wirth, 1983; 1 Letter (Box 75)
  - Hay, Harry - Wirth, 1994; 3 Items (Box 75)
  - Huber, Laurel - Wirth (re Robert Schlick), 2008; Several Items (Box 75)
    Material concerning the wedding of Robert Schlick to Pamela Bianco, which occurred at Gumby's Book Studio around 1929.
  - Jenkins, Raymond - Wirth, 1987; 1 Note (Box 75)
  - Kellner, Bruce - Wirth, 1982-2003; 31 Items (Box 75)
    15 Letters from Kellner to Wirth 8 Cards from Kellner to Wirth 5 Retained draft copies of letters from Wirth to Kellner 2 Printouts of email messages from Wirth to Kellner 1 Clipping See also: Gay Rebel files
  - Lewis, David Levering - Wirth, 1989-1996; Several Items (Box 76)
    Correspondence mostly relating to the publication of "Smoke, Lilies & Jade" in THE HARLEM RENAISSANCE READER; it was inadvertently truncated in the first printing.
  - Marr, Warren II to Wirth, 1986-1987; 3 Items (Box 76)
  - McBreen, Ellen, 1995-1998; Several Items (Box 76)
    Correspondence relating to McBreen's articles.
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Daphne Arnstein, 1972; 2 Letters (Box 76)
    Correspondence concerning a job for Nugent.
  - Monaco, Charles to William Monaco, 1946; 1 Letter (Box 76)
  - Nugent Birthday 1986, Several Items (Box 76)
    Draft invitation, address cards, directions, responses & thank-you notes from Paul England, Eileen Artaseise, Margaret Cole, Faith Berry, Daphne Arnstein, Njambi McQueen, Eunice Weed, & Fr. Val La France
  - Ortiz, Anthony from Wirth, 1987; 1 Item (Box 76)
    Copy of a note from Wirth to Ortiz
  - Perez, Grace (Rodriguez) to Wirth, 1987-88; 1 Letter, 1 Postcard (Box 76)
  - Perez, Jerry from Wirth, ca 1987; 1 Item (Box 76)
    Draft of a letter
  - Robinson, Henry to Wirth, 1987-1989; 3 Letters (Box 76)
  - Silberman, Seth - Wirth, 1991-1994; Several Items (Box 76)
    Several letters, Silberman thesis prospectus on Nugent,
  - Singh, Amritjit - Wirth, 2002; Several Items (Box 76)
    Printouts of email exchanges between Singh & Wirth about Nugent, Wallace Thurman, and their relationship; drafts of Singh's application for a Schomburg fellowship.
  - Smith, Catherine Parsons - Wirth, 1994; 4 Items (Box 76)
    1. Query from Smith concerning Harold Bruce Forsythe, whom she believes to be Nugent 2. Response from Wirth 3. Acknowledgement by Smith 4. Letter from Smith to Wirth stating that she has established that Forsythe and Nugent are not the same person.
  - Taylor, Robert from Wirth, 1984; 1 Item (Box 77)
    Copy of a letter
  - Van Notten - Wirth, 1988-94; Numerous Items (Box 77)
  - Van Notten - Wirth, 1992-94; Several Items (Box 77)
    Draft of Van Notten's Chapter 3; Wirth's comments on Chapter 2 & 3; other correspondence.
  - Van Notten - Wirth, 1993; 4 Items (Box 77)
    Cover letter to Wirth; draft of Chapter 4; Wirth comment on Chapter 4; notes on Nugent's bio.
  - Van Notten - Wirth, 1993; 2 Items (Box 78)
    Cover letter & draft of Chapter 5
  - Van Notten - Wirth, 1993-94; Several Items (Box 78)
    Drafts of Chapter 6 & 7; letters; Wirth's notes; invitation to Van Notten's thesis defense.
  - Weiss, Burton - Wirth, 1986; 1 Letter with enclosures (Box 78)
  - Willis, Steve - Wirth, 1999-2006; Numerous Items (Box 78)
    Letters and offprints of e-mail messages concerning Willis' play, "Passing Ceremonies
  - ------, Olive to Grace Marr, 1948; 1 Postcard (Box 78)
- Subject files, 1927-1986; Series X; (7 boxes)
  Subject files consist of materials related to or collected by Bruce Nugent.
  - Access Stage Media Guild, 1977-78; Numerous Items (Box 79)
  - Alston, Charles, 1977; 1 Item (Box 79)
    Text of eulogy for Alston by George Gregory
  - Arnstein, Nelson, 1973; 2 Items (Box 79)
    Essay on Richard Wright by Arnstein; printed "thank you" to friends from Arnstein's parents to friends on occasion of his entry into medical school.
  - Art, Numerous Items (Box 79)
    Announcements & /invitations to openings
  - Astrology/Spirituality/Self Help, Numerous Items (Box 79)
    Solicitations & ads
  - Astrology/Spirituality/Self Help, Several Items (Box 80)
  - Bands of Steel, 1970-1971; 8 Items (Box 80)
    Bands of Steel was an organization founded by Daphne Arnstein to sponsor the formation of steel bands among urban youth. Nugent was on the Board of Directors. It arose out of her Caribbean travels. Nugent designed graphics for the group.
  - Beam, Joseph, 1984; 1 Item (Box 80)
    Xerox copy of Beam's article "Speaking jfor Ourselves: Interviews with Three Black Gay Men" from Gay News, October 25, 1984
  - Before Stonewall, 1985; 3 Iems (Box 80)
    Brochure, New York Times ad & review
  - Berube, Allen, 198; 1 Item (Box 80)
    February/March 1983 issue of Mother Jones magazine, which contains the essay "Coming Out Under Fire" by Allen Berube. Fine condition.
  - Betti, Silvio, 1985; 2 Items (Box 80)
    Postcard & handout for an exhibition of Betti's works on paper at the Cathedral of St. John the Divine.
  - Books, 2 Items (Box 80)
    Ads
  - Black and White Men Together; Men of All Colors Together/New York, 1985-1986; 5 Items (Box 80)
    Newsletters, flyers
  - BWMT Convention 1983, 10 Items (Box 80)
    Convention materials
  - CLA (College Language Association), 1982, 1985; 2 Items (Box 80)
    Convention programs
  - Clippings, Misc. Newspaper, Numerous Items (Box 80)
  - Dance, 3 Items (Box 80)
    Clipping, flyers
  - De Sola, Carla, 1980; 1 Item (Box 80)
    Wedding program. Carla De Sola is the daughter of Helen Winner De Sola
  - De Sola, Helen Winner, 1975; 1 Item (Box 80)
  - Duran, Angel, Numerous Items (Box 80)
    Materials relating to Duran, Nugent's roommate in Hoboken
  - Ellington, Duke, 1976; 1 Item (Box 81)
    Concert Program "Ellington is Forever" with The Duke Ellington Orchestra, Dave Brubeck, Sarah Vaughan, Joe Williams, and The Hampton Choir. Fine condition
  - Erotica, 6 Items (Box 81)
    Photographs of mildly erotic drawings featuring well-muscled sailors
  - Film, 1971; 1 Item (Box 81)
    Flyer for "The Voice of La Raza
  - FIRE II, 1983, 1984; 2 Items (Box 81)
    Issues of FIRE II, a student publication at Trenton State University. One issue is inscribed to Nugent by Jamesj Chambers, advisor to the publication.
  - Forty Acres and A Mule, 1970; 4 Items (Box 81)
    Volume 3, No. 2-3 & Volume 5, Nos. 5, 7, 9 of this periodical published by the students in the educational program of the New York Urban League
  - Garber, Eric, 3 Items (Box 81)
    Mimeographed typescript of "Tain't Nobody's Business. Xeroxed typescript of "Buffet Flats" Flyer
  - Gay Pornography, Numerous Items (Box 81)
    Advertisements
  - Golden Legacy, 1967; 1 Item (Box 81)
    Issue #2 of Golden Legacy Illustrated History Magazine. "The Saga of Harriet Tubman
  - Greaves, William, 1974; 1 Item (Box 81)
    Flyer for From These Roots
  - Gumby Sonnets, 1 Leaf (Box 81)
    Typescript of one of L.S. Alexander Gumby's sonnets. Gumby's notoriously bad spelling is in evidence.
  - WITHDRAWN (Box 81)
  - Harlem Nightlife & Jazz, 1 Item (Box 81)
    Xerox copy of part of a large-format, illustrated publication. (Title unknown.)
  - Hedgerow Theatre, 1985; 1 Leaf (Box 82)
    Poem lamenting the destruction of the Hedgerow Theatre's building by Gail Cohen.
  - Hoboken, 1985; 2 Items (Box 82)
    Campaign materials for Tom Vezzeti, candidate for mayor of Hoboken.
  - House of Marr, 2 Items (Box 82)
  - Hughes, Langston, 3 Items (Box 82)
    Materials relating to films about Hughes and Kenneth Neilson's collection of Hughes materialsN
  - Hutson, Jean Blackwell, 1984; 1 Item (Box 82)
    Program for a tribute to Ms. Hutson at the Schomburg Center.
  - Hypnosis, 1961; 1 Item (Box 82)
    Disguised Hypnosis" by Jason Whiting. Mimeographed 22-page booklet published by the Hypnotic-Aids Supply Company
  - IFCO News, 1973; 3 Items (Box 82)
    3 issues of the bimonthly publication of the Interreligious Foundation for Community Organization.
  - IPSAAW, 1984; 1 Item (Box 82)
    Invitation to a program sponsored by the Institute for the Preservation and Study of African American Writing.
  - Italy, ca 1976; 2 Items (Box 82)
    Newspaper clipping about the Etruscan Tombs & a mimeographed essay about travel in Italy.
  - Jackman, Harold, 1961; 3 Items (Box 82)
    Announcement of Jackman's death; clipping of Jackman's NY Times obituary; mimeographed invitation to a fund-raising concert by Raoul Abdul for the Harold Jackman Memorial Committee.
  - Jenkins, Raymond, 2 Items (Box 82)
    Christmas cards designed by Jenkins
  - Jeter, William C., Jr., 1970, 1976; Several Items (Box 82)
    Writings by Jeter, unemployment claim documents, drug prescription, ticket stubs
  - Kay, Bernard, 1957, 1974; Several Items (Box 82)
  - Langston Hughes Society, 1984; 2 Items (Box 82)
    Minutes of meeting of 4/19/1984; Treasurer's report 7/15/1984
  - Language Study, 3 Items (Box 82)
    Extensive notes
  - La Roche, Julia Bruce English, 1983; 2 Items (Box 83)
    Washington Post obituary, memorial article in the "Foreign Language Bulletin" of the D.C. Public Schools
  - Madison Cafe, Hoboken, 2 Items (Box 83)
    Postcard photo of the interior; brunch menu
  - Male Physique, 1 Item (Box 83)
    Magazine photo
  - Marr, Charles, 1952; 1 Postcard (Box 83)
    Advertisment addressed to Marr
  - Marr, James, Several Items (Box 83)
    Letters to and from Marr; a holograph story fragment
  - Marr, Warren II, 1969; 1 Item (Box 83)
    Xerox copy of a letter to "Co-worker" as chairman of the Amistad Research Foundation New York Committee, of which Nugent is listed as a member.
  - Mason, Frank, 1979, 1986; 2 Items (Box 83)
    Invitations to art openings.
  - Menta, Steve, 1 Item (Box 83)
    Newspaper clipping
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1970; 1 Item (Box 83)
    Booklet for the Met's centennial celebration. Corner stained, else fine.
  - Miscellaneous, Several Items (Box 83)
  - Music, 4 Items (Box 83)
    Programs & announcements of performances
  - Other Countries, 1987; 1 Item (Box 83)
    1 Flyer announcing a performance
  - Perez, Sammy, 1 Item (Box 83)
    Birth Certificate, date crudely altered
  - Pietri, Pedro, 1973; 1 Item (Box 83)
    Incomplete xerox copy of Pietri's book of poetry, Puerto Rican Obituary.
  - Plexus/Sandro Dernini, 1984-1986; Numerous Items (Box 83)
    Programs, flyers, etc. for events produced by Plexus/Shuttle Theatre.
  - Political Solicitations, 1970, 1985, 1986; 3 Items (Box 83)
  - Porgy, 1927; 1 Item (Box 83)
    November 5, 1927 issue of The Saturday Review, which contains a review of Porgy.
  - Pornography, 4 Items (Box 83)
    Includes a copy of Syndicate Sex by Sean.
  - Race Issues, 2 Items (Box 84)
  - Ratliff, Autry Davis, 2 Items (Box 84)
    1. Resume 2. Program for "The Birds"
  - Riley, Jay, 1 Item (Box 84)
    Resume
  - Robeson, Paul, 1976; 1 Item (Box 84)
    Village Voice Obituary
  - Robinson, Henry, Several Items (Box 84)
    Typescipts of numerous poems, each on a single page; copies of 2 essays; a copy of Selected Poems by Powhatan Robinson (Berkeley: Explorations Press, 1976)
  - Rome, 2 Items (Box 84)
  - Rosicrucian, 1 Pamphlet (Box 84)
    Personal and Private Instructions in the Rosicrucian Art of Absent Healing." San Jose, n.d. (12 pp.)
  - Rosmini, John, 1954; 1 Leaf (Box 84)
    Poem by Rosmini. Copy of the typescript, with corrections.
  - St. Peters Church, 3 Items (Box 84)
    2 Flyers for "All Nite Soul
  - Schomburg Center, 4 Items (Box 84)
    Invitations to events; 60th Anniversary Tribute Publication (48 pp)
  - Storey, David, 1 Item (Box 84)
    First 2 pages (1 leaf) of an interview with Storey published in the Transatlantic Review 33/34
  - Theatre, 3 Items (Box 84)
    Flyers; clipping
  - Thompson, James W. (Abba Elethea), Several Items (Box 85)
    Typescripts & Galleys of some of Thompson's poems; review of a dance concert (1971), 2 versions of the program of the La Mama production of Thompson's choreopoem Songs for My Sisters.
  - Thompson, James W. (Abba Elethea), Several Items (Box 85)
  - Thompson, James W. (Abba Elethea), 1972; 1 Item (ca 50 Leaves) (Box 85)
    Photocopy of the typescript of Fire in the Flesh, Thompson's first book
  - Thorp, Willard, 1 Item (Box 85)
    Xerox copy of Thorpe's essay "The Well of English, Now Defiled
  - Tom of Finland, 1973; 1 Booklet (Box 85)
    Ringo & the Renegades NY: QQ Publishing, 1973. (ponographic publication)
  - Trujillo, Patrick, 1984-1986; Several Items (Box 85)
    3 xerox copies of works by Trujillo, signed 4 exhibition announcements, signed or inscribed 4 collages, signed, 3 with notes to Nugent or Thomas Wirth on the verso. 1 endorsement letter from Alvin Smith 1 decorated envelope, signed
  - Urban League, 1969; 1 Item (Box 85)
    Invitation to a fund-raiser for the New York Urban League
  - Valentino, Rudolph, 1 Item (Box 85)
    Photo of Valentino clipped from a newspaper
  - Vera, Italo, 1985; 2 Items (Box 85)
    A medical bill and a typed note by Vera in Spanish. Vera, from Equador, was one of Nugent's sexual interests.
  - Vidor, King, 1982; 1 Item (Box 85)
    New York Times obituary
  - Whipper, Leigh, 1968; 1 Item (Box 85)
    Clipping from the NY Times "Character Actor, 91, Is Honored at the St. Regis
- Photographs, 1880s-1986; Series XI; 7 boxes + 1 broadside folder
  - Aaronoff, Herman ("Chaim"), 1977; 6 Snapshots (Box 86)
    4 Poloroid Color Snapshots (4" x 4") 2 Color Snapshots (4.7" x 3.5")
  - Agor, Al, 1 Photograph (Box 86)
    Nude Physique. Probably by Bernard Kay. (4.6" x 4")
  - Allen, Irving, ca 1985; 2 Color Poloroid Snapshots (Box 86)
    By RBN
  - Anastois, Teddy, 1971; 2 Photographs (Box 86)
    Poloroid Snapshot (2.5" x 3.5") Restaurant Souvenir Photograph by Planetary Photo (Riverboat, Empire State Bldg) (10" x 8")
  - Arnstein, Daphne & Children, 3 Color Snapshots (5" x 3.5") (Box 86)
  - Arnstein, Nelson, 1 Studio Portrait (8" x 10") (Box 86)
    Carlos'N Charlie's studio, Acapulco, Mexico. RBN portrait of Arnstein was created from this photo.
  - Barri, Robert, 1 Studio Portrait (3.5" x 5.5") (Box 86)
  - Barrow, Muriel Ives, 1 Studio Portrait (8" x 10") (Box 86)
    Inscribed to RBN by Barrow.
  - Barthe, Richmond, 2 Inscribed Photographs; 1 Snapshot (Box 86)
  - Bishop, Glen, 1 Nude Physique Photograph (7.5" x 9.3") (Box 86)
  - Bontemps, Arna with Students, 1 Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 86)
    Photographer: Warren Marr II
  - Catrambone, John, c. 1984; 2 Glossy Studio Head Shots (8" x 10") (Box 86)
  - Cats, 6 Snapshots (Box 86)
  - Chaparro, Nelson, c. 1983; 1 Poloroid Snapshot (Box 86)
    Chaparro was a busboy at the Maidson Cafe in Hoboken.
  - Cullen, Countee, c 1929; 1 Studio Portrait (8" x 10") (Box 86)
    Photograph by James L. Allen. Inscribed by Cullen "To Bruce -- Who without this might forget. / Countee". The photographer's label "Allen/ N.Y." inked by hand in white on the print is barely visible. Age toned, else near fine.
  - D'Ambrosio, Tony, "21 Snapshots; 4 Passport-Type Portraits (1.5" x 2"); 1 Enlargement (8" x 10")" (Box 86)
    One of the snapshots is of D'Ambrosio's daughter. The enlargement is blurred; parts of the emulsion are flaking.